<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<topics xmlns:r="http://www.r-project.org">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../Docs/XSL/Todo.xsl" ?> 
<topic>
<title>General</title>
<items>

<item>
How to get fromXML(node) recognize that there is mapping
from the element name to a class.
<br/>
Do we define a class for the element?
</item>

<item status="fixed">
Defining ObjectType in kml21.xsd doesn't use classes ID and NCName.
The PrimitiveSchemaType in sch[[1]]$ObjectType@slotTypes[[1]]@type
has a value for Rname that is "character" and not ID
</item>

<item>
In processing egquery.xsd, eGCQueryResultType doesn't recognize
the maxOccurs for the slot named ResultItem (with @type ResultItemType) and so just has one rather than a list
of them.
<br/>
After we readSchema(), we have the correct information. So it is when we define the class.
The call to createClassRepresentation() returns "ResultItemType" for the second slot
rather than a list of these.  We should define a new RestrictedListType or something
that induces a new class which is a List-Of-ResultItemType objects.
This calls mapSchemaTypeToS().
If this creates a new class description, we have to ensure that is defined.
So we should do this earlier in the process, i.e. recognize the count
and turn the slotType into RestrictedListType in the ClassDefinition.
So this would be done in <r:func>processSchemaType</r:func>.
The problem is that we have a local element there.
So it is legitimate to leave that as is, unaggressively  describing the element.
</item>

<item>
The default value for the ERROR slot in eGQueryResultType should be character(0), not "".
<br/>
The defaultValues in defineClassDefinition() are correct.
Fix makePrototype().
A simple call to prototype(defaults) gets the right thing. What
does it screw up elsewhere.
</item>

<item>
Create the fromConverter for ClassDefinition and ExtendedClassDefinition.
<br/>
Use createSOAPConverter if possible.
</item>

<item>
Create the enumerated constants for RestrictedStringDefinition.
Make this optionally.
This would create a variable with the same name as the actual value
and be there solely to avoid typos.
</item>

<item status="done">
remove the kml.xml file in inst/samples/
<br/>
in notes/
</item>

<item>
defineClass(pmmlSchema) fails.
</item>

<item>
define classes correponding to Element objects
<br/>
Make this optional.
</item>

<item>
Make fromXML handle optional slots, required slots, 
attributes, attribute default values, etc.
</item>

<item status="low">
Pretty print the description objects.
Define <r:func>show</r:func> methods.
</item>



<item>
SimpleSequenceType: biblio.xsd and Authors
</item>

<item status="low">
Graphical display of class hierarchy.
</item>

<item>
Default value for Extension.row in pmml is wrong - character(). Should be NULL.
<br/>
We now kill these off too, I believe.
</item>

<item>
LatLonBoxType in kml2.1.xsd
Use this as an example of converting an ExtendedClassDefinition into
an R class and a fromConverter.
These elements are optional. So we have to check if they are present.
<br/>
See LatLonBoxType.Rdb in Books/XMLTechnologies/XMLSchema
</item>

<item status="done">
What is the difference between SchemaAnyType (fewer occurrences) and AnySchemaType.
<br/>
I have removed the former now. Test!!!!!
</item>

<item id="string">
Define a "string" class that extends/contains "character".
Problem is that we lose the class of the elements
as they become "character".
</item>

<item>
Have to use a list as the base class for RestrictedListType 
(and SimpleSequenceType) when the element type is a sub-class
of a primitive type, e.g. "string" or "character".  See <ref ref="#string"/>
</item>
</items>
</topic>
</topics>
